Run, Luffy!
‫اهرب يا لوفي‬
No... No way!
‫لا... مستحيل‬
I can't believe it!
‫لا أستطيع تصديق هذا‬
Captain, we're screwed!
‫أيّها القبطان، لا فرصة لنا‬
There's no way to put out the fire!
‫يستحيل إخماد الحريق‬
We gotta give up the ship! We can't flee to the sea!
‫عينا أن نتخلّى عن السّفينة! لا يمكننا الهرب إلى البحر!‬
Damn that king! How could he do this to us?!
‫ذاك الملك اللّعين، كيف أمكنه فعل هذا بنا؟‬
I'll show that bastard!
‫سأري ذلك الوغد‬
Honestly!
‫يا إلهي‬
It's so annoying that the sky in the south is bright even during the night.
‫من المزعج جدًّا أنّ السّماء في الشّمال ساطعة حتّى ليلًا‬
Apologies, Your Majesty. Allow us to close the curtains.
‫آسفون يا صاحب الجلالة. دعنا نغلق السّتار‬
Father, is there a reason the people in Gray Terminal aren't humans?
‫بالمناسبة يا أبي، لِمَ النّاس في المحطة الرمادية ليسوا بشرًا؟‬
Why do they have to get burned?
‫لِمَ يجب أن يُحرقوا؟‬
It is said, "As a man sows, so shall he reap."
‫كما يقول المثل، "من زرع حصد"‬
Think about it.
‫فكّري في الأمر‬
They could have avoided their fate if only they were born nobles.
‫أمكنهم تجنّب مصيرهم بأن يولدوا نبلاء‬
Born nobles?
‫يولدوا نبلاء؟‬
You're right! They should have chosen to be born nobles!
‫معك حقّ! كان يجب أن يختاروا أن يولدوا نبلاء!‬
How dumb of them!
‫إنّهم أغبياء‬
Now, enough about those people. You have to study tomorrow, don't you?
‫يكفي من أولئك النّاس، عليك أن تدرسي من أجل الغد‬
You'd better get to bed.
‫من الأفضل أن تأوي للفراش‬
Okay!
‫حسنًا‬
Goodnight.
‫طابت ليلتك‬
This side's blocked, too!
‫لا مهرب من هذا الجانب‬
We're losing ground to stand on!
‫نواصل فقدان المساحة‬
I don't wanna die here!
‫لا أريد الموت هنا‬
Think those old guys got out okay?
‫أتساءل إن كان أولئك الرّجال العجزة هربوا بسلام‬
We can't worry about anyone else right now!
‫هذا ليس الوقت لتقلق على الغير‬
Crap! I don't even know where we are!
‫سحقًا! لا أدري حتّى أين أنا!‬
Who said you brats could escape?!
‫من قال أنّه يمكنكما الهرب أيّها الشّقيّان؟‬
Bluejam!
‫بلوجام‬
Why are you still here after setting the fire?!
‫لِمَ ما زلت هنا بعد أن أضرمت النّار؟‬
You should be long gone by now!
‫ينبغي أن تكون قد هربت الآن‬
Shut up, you little shit!
‫اخرس أيّها الحثالة‬
We're at our wits' end, you see.
‫أمرنا ميؤوس منه‬
We're in a bit of a pickle.
‫لدينا معضلة غير متوقّعة‬
Humans are strange creatures, aren't they?
‫البشر مخلوقات غريبة، أليس كذلك؟‬
When you hit rock bottom, you can't stop laughing.
‫عندما تدرك الحضيض، لا تكفّ عن الضّحك‬
They're being weird.
‫إنّهم يتصرّفون بغرابة‬
Luffy! We gotta run!
‫لوفي، لنذهب‬
Stop them!
‫لا تدعوهما يهربان‬
We worked together as crewmates, after all!
‫عملنا معًا، نحن أصدقاء‬
Now, we need to die together!
‫علينا أن نموت معًا‬
We're not gonna die with you! Never in a million years!
‫لا نريد أن نموت معك! أبدًا!‬
Cold shoulder, huh?
‫أنت قاسٍ حقًّا‬
Come to think of it, you still haven't told me where you stash your treasure.
‫بالتّفكير في الأمر، لم تخبرني أين تخفيان كنزكما‬
I'll rescue it from the fire for you. So, tell me where it is!
‫سأنقذه من أجلكما قبل أن تطوله النّار‬ ‫لذا أخبراني عن مكانه‬
You're about to die and all you care about is treasure?!
‫حياتك في خطر وكلّ همّك هو الكنز؟‬
Well, if you don't care, then tell me.
‫إن كنت لا تهتمّ، أخبرني أين هو‬
You've really lost it.
‫لقد جننت‬
Not salvaging it would be such a waste!
‫إن كنت لن تحصل عليه فستكون خسارة‬
If we just stand here, it'll get reduced to charcoal like my ship!
‫إلّم نفعل شيئًا، سيتحوّل إلى فحم كما سفينتي‬
What a waste.
‫يا لها من خسارة‬
Don't be dumb! That treasure is–
‫لا تكن سخيفًا! الكنز...‬
Fine! I'll tell you.
‫حسنًا، سأخبرك‬
Ace! You and Sabo worked so long to–
‫إيس! أنت وسابو أمضيتما الكثير من الوقت في...‬
Sabo would understand!
‫سابو سيتفهّم‬
Right now your life...
‫الأهمّ الآن هي حياتك...‬
Right now our lives are more important!
‫بل الأهمّ الآن هي حياتنا‬
Ace...
‫إيس...‬
We have six-years-worth of treasure in this tree.
‫إنّنا نخبّئ كنزنا من آخر ستّ سنوات في هذه الشّجرة‬
I see.
‫فهمت‬
Don't cry!
‫لا تبك‬
It's all right. This isn't where it ends.
‫لا بأس. هذه ليست النّهاية‬
What're you doing?! I told you where it is!
‫ماذا تفعل؟ أخبرتك عن مكانه‬
You're right. "This isn't where it ends."
‫معك حقّ، هذه ليست النّهاية‬
There's a chance you lied, so you're coming with us!
‫ما يعني أنّك ربّما تكذب. عليك أن تأتي معنا‬
No way! We'll lose our chance to get out of here!
‫مستحيل! حينها سيكون الوقت قد فات على الهرب!‬
Just go on your own!
‫لِمَ لا تذهبون بأنفسكم؟‬
You don't wanna mess with me right now.
‫لا أنصحك بالعبث معي الآن‬
Even if it means robbing a few kids,
‫وإن عنى ذلك أن أسرق من الأطفال‬
I swore I'd make a comeback and get my revenge on the nobles.
‫أنا عازم على ردّ الصّاع‬ ‫لكي أنتقم من النّبلاء‬
And your brother is one of them.
‫وأخوك أحدهم‬
They think they're so special,
‫يحسبون أنفسهم استثناء‬
looking down on us like we're nothing but trash!
‫ويحتقرون الغير كما لو أنّنا قمامة‬
Sabo doesn't think like that!
‫سابو لا يفكّر هكذا‬
He's no different, you idiot kid!
‫إنّه مثلهم أيّها الأحمق‬
He spent time with you because it made him feel superior!
‫كان معكما فقط ليشعر بالتّفوّق‬
That's not true!
‫هذا غير صحيح‬
His parents are loaded.
‫أبواه ثريّان‬
He wants for nothing!
‫ليس بحاجة للقلق بشأن أيّ شيء‬
This was all a cheap thrill for him.
‫كانت مجرّد تسلية بالنّسبة له‬
He was looking down at you, holding his nose while laughing to himself!
‫كان يحتقركما ويضحك في سرّه‬
Stop badmouthing Sabo!
‫كفّ عن الإساءة إلى سابو‬
Yeah, Sabo just wants to be free!
‫أجل، يريد سابو أن يكون حرًّا فحسب‬
You little shit!
‫أيّها الحثالة‬
Luffy!
‫لوفي‬
I'm gonna kill you!
‫سأقتلك‬
Let go of me!
‫دعني‬
Don't you touch Luffy!
‫إيّاك أن تلمس لوفي‬
Luffy! You okay?!
‫لوفي! هل أنت بخير؟!‬
What did you do?!
‫ماذا فعلت؟‬
Dammit...
‫سحقًا...‬
Sneaky runt!
‫أيّها الشّقيّ المخيف‬
You looking to make a fool outta me too?!
‫هل تريد أن تسخر منّي أنت أيضًا؟‬
Shut up, scumbag!
‫اخرس أيّها الحثالة‬
You bastard!
‫أيّها الوغد‬
Ace!
‫إيس‬
Don't do it!
‫لا تفعل‬
Dadan!
‫دادان‬
Stop it, you sea monster!
‫توقّف يا مخبول البحر‬
Let go of Ace!
‫دع إيس وشأنه‬
Why are you guys here?!
‫ماذا تفعلون هنا؟‬
We finally found you!
‫وجدناكما أخيرًا‬
These are pretty serious wounds, Luffy! Are you okay?
‫إنّك مصاب بشدّة يا لوفي، هل أنت بخير؟‬
Dogra...
‫دوغرا...‬
I don't see Sabo anywhere!
‫لا أرى سابو في أيّ مكان‬
Sabo went home. He's not here.
‫عاد سابو إلى بيته. ليس هنا‬
Ace!
‫إيس‬
You must be that boss monkey from Mt. Colubo!
‫أنت زعيمة القردة من جبل كولبو‬
I'm the mountain bandit, Dadan!
‫أنا لصّة الجبل دادان‬
I'm not sure why, but for better or worse, I foster these brats!
‫لا أدري لماذا، لكنّني مسجّلة كوالدتهما بالتّبنّي‬
Alright, fellas...
‫حقًّا؟ حسنًا إذًا...‬
Make a run for it!
‫اهربوا‬
– You got it, boss!
‫حاضر‬
Hey, what're you doing?!
‫مهلًا، ماذا تفعل؟‬
Ace, hurry up!
‫إيس، أسرع‬
Ace!
‫إيس‬
I...
‫أنا...‬
won't run!
‫لن أهرب‬
What're you saying, Ace?! Don't try to fight him!
‫ماذا تقول يا إيس؟ لا تحاول قتاله‬
Bluejam's a real villain!
‫بلوجام مجرم حقيقيّ‬
Kids like you couldn't possibly beat a guy like him!
‫لا يمكن لطفل مثلك هزيمته‬
M-Me too!
‫د-دعني أقاتل أيضا -‬ ‫لا تفعل يا لوفي -‬
You guys... Take Luffy and go on ahead!
‫أنتم، خذوا لوفي واسبقونا‬
B-Boss!
‫أ-أيّتها الزّعيمة‬
As for me, I'm bringing Ace back home!
‫سأتحمّل مسؤوليّة إعادة إيس إلى الدّيار‬
– Boss!
‫أيّتها الزّعيمة‬
Get going!
‫اذهبوا‬
– Y-Yes, ma'am!
‫حـ-حاضر‬
Ace!
‫إيس‬
Boss! You'd better make it back!
‫أيّتها الزّعيمة! عودي إلى الدّيار بأمان!‬
A woman and a child.
‫امرأة وطفل‬
If you overestimate your abilities, you'll pay in blood!
‫إن بالغتما في تقدير قدرتكما‬ ‫ستتعرّضان للأذى فحسب‬
Only the strong and the cowardly survive in battle!
‫فقط القويّ والجبان ينجيان في الحرب‬
The brave always die.
‫الشّجاع مصيره الموت‬
Is that so?
‫هكذا إذًا؟‬
Fools!
‫يا لك من حمقاء‬
Damn!
‫سحقًا‬
We're goners! The flames are all around us!
‫أنا هالك! النّار من كلّ جهة!‬
How could this happen to us?!
‫كيف حدث هذا فجأةً؟‬
It's hot! It's hot!
‫ساخن! المكان ساخن -!‬ ‫لا مهرب -‬
There's nothing we can do!
‫علينا أن نستسلم‬
What just happened?
‫ماذا حدث توًّا؟‬
There's a path!
‫إنّه طريق‬
That explosion made a path!
‫خلّف الانفجار طريقًا‬
Whatever the reason, we're in luck!
‫لا أدري ما الّذي يجري لكنّ هذا ممتاز‬
Hey! Look! It's a ship!
‫انظروا، هنالك سفينة‬
I see a ship!
‫أرى سفينة‬
This path leads up to the shore!
‫يقود هذا الطّريق إلى الشّاطئ‬
We can follow it out of here!
‫يمكننا الهرب إن اتّبعناه‬
Run before the fire returns!
‫لنذهب قبل أن تعود النّار‬
Vhaat an awful country, burning the land and its residents!
‫كم هم فظيعون لإحراق المنطقة وأهاليها ما زالوا هناك‬
By the vayy,
‫بالمناسبة‬
vhyy did you know the goings on of such a remote kingdom in the East Blue?
‫كيف عرفت الوضع في بلادٍ نائية في الأزرق الشّرقيّ؟‬
Vhaat is so special about this place, hm?
‫هل من شيء خاصّ في هذه البلاد؟‬
This country is a microcosm of our world's future.
‫هذه البلاد خير مثال لكيف سيكون العالم في المستقبل‬
Happiness is but a pipe dream in a world that eliminates those deemed unnecessary.
‫لا سعادة في عالم يتخلّصون فيه من غير المرغوب بهم‬
I swear to you all, I will change this world someday!
‫يومًا، سأغيّر العالم‬
If I stay here... I'll never be free!
‫إن بقيت هنا... لن أكون حرًّا أبدًا‬
Even in a country like this, children will be born.
‫حتّى في بلادٍ كهذه، يوجد أطفال وُلدوا بريئين‬
Those of you who are willing to fight by my side for freedom, come aboard my ship!
‫ليصعد منكم من يريد القتال من أجل الحرّيّة‬
– Yeah!
‫نعم...‬
Is the town really safe? The flames look like they could consume us at any moment!
‫هل هذه البلدة آمنة حقًّا؟‬ ‫يبدو أنّ النّار قد تبتلع البلدة في أيّة لحظة‬
Is there any chance they'd let us up into High Town?
‫هل من طريقة لدخول المدينة العليا؟‬
Zero.
‫لا‬
Not even a bug could enter—nobles only!
‫لا يسمحون حتّى للحشرات بالدّخول، فقط النّبلاء‬
– Boss!
‫أيّتها الزّعيمة -‬
Ace!
‫إيس‬
Boss!
‫أيّتها الزّعيمة‬
Ace and Dadan...
‫إيس ودادان لم يرجعا من المحطة الرمادية المحترقة‬
Take it easy and wait, Luffy.
‫هوّن عليك، انتظر يا لوفي‬ ‫لم تتعاف بعد، إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟‬
I'm gonna go look for Ace and Dadan!
‫عليّ أن أذهب للبحث عن إيس ودادان‬
Don't be so reckless!
‫لا يمكنك ذلك‬
Your wounds are really deep. Just take it easy and relax.
‫إصاباتك بليغة. عليك أن ترتاح جيّدًا‬
Right now, Gray Terminal is crawling with soldiers cleaning up after the fire.
‫هنالك الكثير من القوّات في المحطة الرمادية‬ ‫الآن للاعتناء بالفوضى الّتي خلّفها الحريق‬
And they're not just "cleaning up" the burned trash...
‫فهم لا يتخلّصون من القمامة المحترقة فقط‬
they're "cleaning up" any survivors they find as well.
‫بل وحتّى النّاجين‬
If you go there now, you'll get killed.
‫سيقتلونك إن ذهبت إلى هناك‬
But...!
‫لكن...‬
I wanna see Ace!
‫أريد رؤية إيس‬
I'm sure Sabo's worried about us too!
‫أعلم أنّ سابو قلق بشأننا أيضًا‬
Our orders are to shoot any survivors on sight.
‫إن وجدنا ناجٍ، سنطلق عليه على الفور‬
As if anyone survived this!
‫لا يوجد أيّ ناجٍ‬
Still, I expected a lot more corpses than this...
‫لكن لا توجد جثث كثيرة كما توقّعت‬
It was one hell of a fire! It must've torched them, bones and all.
‫كان حريقًا هائلًا. ربّما حرق حتّى عظامهم‬
I was really worried that the fire would jump the wall and reach the city yesterday.
‫كنت متوتّرًا البارحة وظننت أنّ‬ ‫النّار قد تصل لهذا الجانب من الجدار‬
I heard even Bluejam's ship caught fire.
‫يقال أنّ سفينة بلوجام كانت تحترق أيضًا‬
I'm glad those no-good thugs didn't escape the blaze.
‫من الجيّد أنّ أولئك الجانحين حُرقوا أيضًا‬
Run all you want, you can't get away, Sabo!
‫مهما هربت من البيت فلن تستطيع الابتعاد أبدًا يا سابو‬
The entire military and every single police officer have your picture now!
‫كلّ ضبّاط الشّرطة والقوّات يملكون صورتك الآن‬
You will never get out of High Town...
‫لن تخرج من المدينة العليا أبدًا...‬
much less this house!
‫ولن تخرج حتّى من هذا البيت‬
Discard those uniforms. From here on, you two work for me as his bodyguards.
‫أنتما، غيّرا زيّكما وابدآ العمل هنا كحارسين‬
But sir, our duties...
‫لكن لدينا مهامّنا...‬
Nothing is beyond a nobleman's power.
‫لا يوجد شيء يعجز عنه رجل نبيل‬
I'll get the approval of your superiors.
‫سأحصل على موافقة ضابطكما المسؤول‬
You will hole up in your room and fully educate yourself in your role as a noble.
‫سابو، عليك أن تحصّن نفسك في غرفتك‬
No!
‫لا!‬
As I've told you, all it takes is a single word to get what I want.
‫كما تعلم، يمكنني أن أفعل ما أريد بمجرّد إعطاء أمر‬
Imagine what I could do to you... or to your two friends.
‫لذا بإمكاني تولّي أمرك أو ذلكما الاثنين بسهولة‬
Understood?
‫أكلامي مفهوم؟‬
Dad...
‫أبي...‬
Ace... Luffy...
‫إيس... لوفي...‬
If you understand, then commit to a change of heart and study hard like Sterry.
‫لذا عليك أن تصلح سبيلك وتدرس جيّدًا كستيلي‬
And now, go forth and study; bring happiness to the mother and father who gave you life.
‫و ادرس لكي تجعل والديك‬ ‫اللّذان أنجباك سعيدين‬
This, in turn, is your happiness.
‫لأنّ ذلك سيسعدك أنت أيضًا‬
Do you not agree?
‫ألا تظنّ ذلك؟‬
Father!
‫أبي‬
Don't worry! I'm here for you!
‫لا تقلق! أنا هنا من أجلك!‬
You're so dependable, Sterry!
‫أنت مؤتمن حقًّا يا ستيلي‬
Alright! I'll buy you a marvelous new outfit!
‫حسنًا، دعني أشتري لك بعض الثّياب الفاخرة‬
The ceremony is in two days, after all.
‫لأنّ الحفل بعد غد‬
There, we will see the Celestial Dragon in person!
‫هناك، سنرى التّنّين السّماويّ شخصيًّا‬
Make sure you have your homework finished by tomorrow.
‫سأتفقّد واجبك المنزليّ غدًا‬
Well then, have a wonderful day.
‫حسنًا، طاب يومك‬
Ace... Luffy...
‫إيس... لوفي...‬
There's no way you'd die in a fire like that, right?
‫لا أظنّ أنّكم متّم في الحريق‬
You guys are safe, right?
‫أنتما بخير، أليس كذلك؟‬
I really want to see you.
‫يا ليتني كنت أستطيع رؤيتكما‬
But if I do, I'd only put you in danger again.
‫لكن أدري أنّني سأعرّضكما للخطر إن حاولت رؤيتكما الآن‬
This place is like a birdcage.
‫هذا المكان أشبه بقفص‬
I don't think I can even bear to breathe its stale air any longer.
‫لا أظنّني أستطيع احتمال العيش‬ ‫في هذه البلاد المليئة بالهواء الفاسد‬
What is freedom?
‫ما هي الحرّيّة؟‬
Where can I find it?
‫وأين يمكنني إيجادها؟‬
Well then, we're off!
‫حسنًا، سنغادر الآن‬
I leave Sabo in your care.
‫اعتن بسابو جيّدًا‬
Very well, Master.
‫حاضر‬
On this day, one of the Grand Line's very own world nobles visits the Kingdom of Goa.
‫يوم زيارة أحد نبلاء العالم من الغراند لاين‬ ‫لمملكة غوا قد حان‬
A grand ceremony has been prepared to welcome the ship.
‫حيث تمّ تحضير حفل فخم لوصول السّفينة‬
Hey, wait! Someone's boat is sailing out!
‫انظروا! ثمّة سفينة تغادر الميناء!‬
What?
‫ماذا؟ -‬ ‫أهو قارب صيد؟ -‬
Hey! Turn back! You'll disrupt the ceremony!
‫أنت! عد إلى هنا! لا تعترض الحفل!‬
It's a child!
‫إنّه طفل! ثمّة طفل على السّفينة!‬
A child?
‫طفل؟ أتساءل من أيّ عائلة هو‬
A child...?
‫طفل؟‬
The weather's great!
‫الطقس رائع‬
The perfect day for a voyage!
‫إنّه يوم مثاليّ للإبحار‬
Hey, hey! That's my ship!
‫لا! إنّه لي! سرق أحدهم قارب الصّيد خاصّتي!‬
Look! He's flying a black flag!
‫انظروا! رفع عليه علمًا أسودًا!‬
What, does he think he's a pirate?!
‫هل يظنّ أنّه قرصان؟‬
No way! A kid by himself, a pirate?!
‫مستحيل! لا يمكن لفتى أن يصبح قرصانًا!‬
Where's he heading?
‫إلى أين هو ذاهب؟‬
He'll get in the way of ceremony.
‫إنّه يعطّل الحفل‬
The World Government ship is almost here!
‫ستصل سفينة الحكومة قريبًا‬
Hurry up and do something!
‫أسرع وافعل شيئًا‬
Y-Yes, sir!
‫حـ-حاضر‬
Hey!
‫أنت‬
Hey, you! Get back here this instant!
‫يا ولد، عد إلى هنا فورًا‬
The thing I'm most afraid of is being consumed by this country...
‫المصير الأكثر رعبًا بالنّسبة لي‬ ‫هو أن أفقد نفسي في هذه البلاد...‬
and becoming someone else!
‫وأصبح أحدًا آخر‬
I'm never going back!
‫لن أعود‬
That's not Sabo, is it?!
‫أذلك سابو على متن السّفينة؟‬
The government ship is here!
‫وصلت سفينة الحكومة‬
What a huge ship!
‫يا لها من سفينة ضخمة‬
Crashing into that would end things real quick.
‫سأموت إن ارتطمت بها‬
Let's avoid that.
‫سأتفادى ذلك‬
To think we get this rare chance to lay eyes on someone so blessed!
‫إنّهم مباركون لدرجة أنّ من النّادر حتّى رؤيتهم‬
I can't believe an honest-to-goodness Celestial Dragon is on that ship!
‫لا أصدّق أنّ أحد التّنانين السّماويّين على متن تلك السّفينة‬
What is that?
‫بالمناسبة، ما ذلك؟‬
It appears to be a simple fishing boat, sir.
‫يبدو ذلك كقارب صيد‬
I can't wait to be the captain of a ship like that someday!
‫سيكون من الجميل أن أكون قبطان سفينة كهذه يومًا‬
Ace isn't dead!
‫إيس لم يمت‬
I know, take it easy. I know how you feel.
‫هوّن عليك، أعلم. أعلم كيف تشعر‬
But you're in no state to go to Gray Terminal, especially with all the troops there.
‫لكن من الخطير جدًّا أن تذهب إلى المحطة الرمادية الآن‬
But...!
‫لكن -‬ ‫من دون لكن، كان حريقًا هائلًا‬
Dogra is already there searching for them, so trust him and wait!
‫ذهب دوغرا إلى هناك للبحث‬ ‫عنهما الآن لذا ثق به وانتظر‬
We're all have a hard time, not just you, Luffy.
‫الجميع يواجهون وقتًا صعبًا، وليس أنت فقط يا لوفي‬
The fishing boat's been hit!
‫أصيب قارب الصّيد -‬ ‫كيف حال الطّفل؟ -‬
He must've angered the Celestial Dragon!
‫لقد أغضب التّنّين السّماويّ‬
Sabo!
‫سابو‬
Crap! The ship caught fire!
‫سحقًا! السّفينة تحترق!‬
Why'd they shoot me like that?!
‫لِمَ أطلقوا عليّ هكذا؟‬
Saint Jalmack! There's a child on that boat!
‫أيّها القدّيس جالماك! هناك طفل على السّفينة!‬
No matter who he is, flying a black flag makes him a pirate.
‫عندما يرفع أحدهم علمًا أسودًا، فهو قرصان أيًّا كان‬
But most importantly...
‫لكن الأهمّ...‬
Dammit!
‫سحقًا‬
How dare that lowly commoner enter the path of my ship?!
‫لا يجب على عامّيّ أن يسير في طريق سفينتي‬
Hey! What was that ship doing?
‫مهلًا، ما الّذي تفعله تلك السّفينة؟‬
This is an important ceremony!
‫هذا حفل مهمّ‬
We don't wanna put the Celestial Dragon in a bad mood!
‫لا نريد تعكير مزاج التّنّين السّماويّ‬
Clean up that flotsam already!
‫أزيحوا حطام السّفينة بسرعة‬
Hey!
‫يا رفاق‬
Hey, everyone, they're...!
‫رفاق، ذلكما الاثنان...‬
What is it?
‫ما الأمر؟‬
They're back!
‫ذلكما الاثنان لقد عادا‬
– Thank goodness!
‫حمدًا لهذا‬
Ace... Boss...
‫إيس... الزّعيمة...‬
She's severely wounded! Hurry up and treat her!
‫إنّها مصابة بشدّة! أسرعوا وعالجوها!‬
Are you okay?
‫هل أنت بخير؟‬
Ace!
‫إيس!‬
Luffy!
‫لوفي!‬
Did you think I was dead?
‫هل ظننت أنّني متّ؟‬
But...!
‫لكن -...‬ ‫لماذا تبكي؟ -‬
You're acting like I died, you idiot!
‫لم أمت أيّها الأحمق‬
Well, now, take it easy. That's enough.
‫على رسلك، هذا يكفي‬
Luffy is just happy.
‫لوفي فرح فحسب‬
Ace, can we ask about the night of the fire?
‫أيمكنني أن أسالك عن ليلة الحريق؟‬
After we left with Luffy,
‫بعد أن غادرنا مع لوفي‬
what happened to you and the boss?
‫ماذا حدث لك وللزّعيمة؟‬
We fought with Bluejam...
‫قاتلنا بلوجام...‬
Somehow, we managed to defeat him...
‫وهزمناه بشقّ الأنفس‬
and we hurried and tried to catch up with you guys...
‫وحاولنا أن نتبعكم على الفور‬
but by then, the path was blocked.
‫لكنّ النّار وقفت حائلًا بيننا‬
Dadan was badly burned.
‫لكنّ دادان حرقت بشكل شديد‬
We hid by the river in the midway forest, safe from the fire.
‫تمكنّا من الوصول إلى ضفّة النّهر في الغابة الوسطى‬
I stole some medicine from town and also found some food.
‫ذهبت إلى البلدة لسرقة بعض‬ ‫الأدوية وأحصل على شيء نأكله‬
It was all I could do to keep Dadan alive.
‫وحاولت إنقاذ حياة دادان‬
Take it easy. I see now.
‫حسنًا، حسنًا، فهمنا‬
Well, I'm glad you both made it out alive.
‫على أيّ حال، أنا مسرور لأنّكما نجوتما‬
Sorry to make you worry.
‫آسفة لإقلاقكم‬
It's crazy what happened to Gray Terminal...
‫لا أصدّق ما حدث في المحطة الرمادية‬
I'm sure Sabo is worried.
‫أتساءل إن كان سابو قلقًا علينا‬
More insolent commoners might show up.
‫قد يظهر عامّيّ وقح آخر في أيّ لحظة‬
Remain vigilant.
‫راقبا جيّدًا‬
– Yes, sir!
‫حاضر‬
I wonder what Sabo's up to.
‫أتساءل كيف يبلي سابو‬
Still, I'm glad Ace came back, and Dadan is getting better.
‫لكنّي مسرور لأنّ إيس عاد ودادان تتعافى‬
Ace, back then...
‫إيس، في تلك اللّحظة...‬
I...
‫أنا...‬
won't run!
‫لن أهرب‬
...why didn't you run?
‫لِمَ لم تهرب؟‬
Sometimes, my blood just begins to boil.
‫لا أستطيع سوى أن أتحمّس أحيانًا‬
I'm afraid that if I run, I'll lose something important.
‫أنا خائف دائمًا أنّه إن هربت‬ ‫سأترك شيئًا مهمًّا خلفي‬
At that moment...
‫في تلك اللّحظة...‬
Luffy was right behind me.
‫كان لوفي خلفي‬
I don't know, but I think that's why.
‫لا أدري لكن أظنّ لذلك السّبب‬
Even when facing an army with no chance at winning...
‫حتّى عندما واجه حشدًا من الأعداء يفوقون طاقته‬
Roger would never flee from the battle.
‫لم يهرب روجر أبدًا‬
Did he have death wish? Running is a viable strategy, too.
‫أكان انتحاريًّا؟ الهرب يعدّ استراتيجيّة أيضًا‬
Regardless, he would never run away...
‫هذا صحيح لكنّه لا يفعل ذلك أبدًا‬
Running away with his crew meant putting all their lives in danger.
‫إن هرب، سيعرّض طاقمه للخطر‬
More accurately, it's not that he never ran...
‫في الواقع، ليس من الصّائب القول‬ ‫أنّه "ما كان ليهرب"‬
he just didn't want to give his enemies a chance to go after his crew.
‫بل لن يدع للعدوّ فرصة لمهاجمة طاقمه‬
When he got like that, Roger became quite the demon.
‫كان يتحوّل إلى شيطان في تلك اللّحظات‬
He was known to crush entire armies just because they badmouthed a friend.
‫دمّر جيش بلادٍ بأكمله ذات مرّة‬ ‫لأنّهم تحدّثوا بسوء عن طاقمه‬
Indeed, he was violent when angry. His temper was short and he was selfish.
‫يصبح عنيفًا عندما يغضب،‬ ‫كان حادّ المزاج وأنانيًّا‬
However, his actions were always motivated by a pure, childlike intention.
‫ومع ذلك، كان ساذجًا وصريحًا كالأطفال في نفس الوقت‬
I bet he had a similar upbringing to Ace.
‫ذلك لأنّ حياته المبكّرة كانت كحياة إيس‬
He truly hated the thought of losing his loved ones.
‫كره أن يخسر من يحبّ‬
Despite living so recklessly, his luck kept him alive long enough to become King of the Pirates.
‫كان أسلوب حياته المتهور والحظ الذي أبقاه على قيد الحياة  ما جعله يصير ملك القراصنة‬
While the world saw him as the worst of the worst, his crew trusted him implicitly.
‫على الرغم من سوء سمعته في جميع أنحاء العالم إلا أن طاقمه وثقوا به ثقةً عمياء‬
Even this old Marine couldn't bring himself to hate Roger.
‫حتّى أنا كجنديّ بحريّة لم أستطع سوى احترامه‬
That's why I decided to raise Ace.
‫ولهذا قرّرت الاعتناء بإيس‬
We're the ones raising him!
‫نحن من نعتني به‬
Huh?! Got something you wanna say?!
‫ماذا؟ أتريدين قول شيء؟‬
No. No problem.
‫لا، لا شيء‬
The people of the world still hate Roger.
‫ما زالت شعوب العالم تكره روجر‬
Even if Ace hates his father, the apple still didn't fall far from the tree.
‫وبينما يكره إيس والده‬ ‫ينطبق عليه مثل "من شابه أباه فما ظلم"‬
Alright... Who's gonna win?
‫حسنًا! لنرَ أيّكما سيفوز...‬
Dogra!
‫دوغرا‬
You went looking for Ace and Dadan, right?
‫كنت تبحث عن إيس ودادان، صحيح؟‬
They both came home!
‫لقد عادا‬
They did? That's really great to hear...
‫حقًّا؟ هذا ممتاز‬
Wh-What?!
‫ماذا؟‬
Sabo is...
‫سابو قد...‬
You liar!
‫كفّ عن الكذب أيّها الأحمق!‬ ‫إيّاك حتّى أن تمزح في ذلك!‬
That's enough, Ace!
‫توقّف يا إيس‬
I'm not lying or joking about it!
‫لستُ أكذب أو أمزح! حدث ذلك فجأةً!‬
It was so sudden that I doubted my own eyes!
‫بالكاد استطعت تصديق ما رأيت‬
I kept thinking it was some kind of bad dream!
‫ظننت أنّني أحلم‬
Cut the crap! Sabo went back to his noble family.
‫اخرس! عاد سابو إلى بيت عائلته!‬
How could he be at sea?!
‫فكيف أمكنه أن يكون في البحر؟‬
That's right! Sabo went back ho–
‫هذا صحيح! عاد إلى بيته!‬
As an outlaw, I understand how he must have felt!
‫يمكن لقاطع طريق مثلي أن يفهم كيف يشعر‬
We all have places we really don't want to go back to!
‫ليس كلّ النّاس يريدون العودة إلى منازلهم‬
Do you think he would've set sail if he was truly happy?
‫لو أنّه كان سعيدًا حقًّا، لما قصد البحر‬
Do you really think he'd fly a pirate flag and set out on his own?!
‫ولَما ذهب إلى البحر وحده رافعًا‬ ‫علمًا أسودًا على سفينته‬
Sabo...
‫سابو...‬
He really wasn't happy!
‫لم يكن سعيدًا‬
Even with parents, I was all by myself.
‫كنتُ وحيدًا حتّى وأنا أملك أبوين‬
Why... Why didn't we try to break him out of there?!
‫لماذا؟ لِمَ لم نعد إلى هناك لإعادته؟‬
Where's the guy who did this to Sabo?! I'm gonna murder him!
‫أين الشّخص الّذي قتل سابو الآن؟ سأقتله‬
Th-The Celestial Dragon?! There's no way you can do th–
‫تـ-تقتل التّنّين السّماويّ؟ هذا مستحيل...‬
I'll avenge him!
‫سأجعله يدفع الثّمن‬
Wait, Ace!
‫انتظر يا إيس‬
Drop it, you little shit!
‫توقّف أيّها الحقير‬
Get off me...
‫تنحّي...‬
Outta my way!
‫تنحّي عن طريقي‬
You talk pretty big for a weakling like yourself!
‫أنّى لك أن تكون بهذه الثّقة‬ ‫مع أنّك لست بتلك القوّة؟‬
What can you even do?! You'll just wind up dead!
‫ماذا يمكنك أن تفعل؟ سيقتلونك فحسب‬
You'll die, and people will forget you by tomorrow because you still haven't amounted to anything!
‫ستموت وسينساك النّاس غدًا‬ ‫ما أنت سوى صبيّ مغمور‬
It was this country— this world—that killed Sabo!
‫قُتل سابو من قبل هذه البلاد! هذا العالم!‬
What can you do?!
‫ماذا يمكنك أن تفعل بشأن ذلك؟‬
Your father's death brought about a new era!
‫غيّر والدك العالم بموته‬
When you become a man of his caliber, you can die whenever the hell you please!
‫عندما تصبح رجلًا بتلك الأهمّيّة‬ ‫حينها افعل ما يحلو لك‬
Go tie this moron up!
‫اربطوا هذا الأحمق‬
Y-Yes, ma'am!
‫حـ-حاضر‬
Sabo!
‫سابو‬
Damn it!
‫سحقًا‬
Shut up! Men aren't supposed to cry like that, Luffy!
‫اخرس! الرّجال لا يبكون يا لوفي!‬
Have you cooled your head a bit, Ace?
‫هل عدت لصوابك يا إيس؟‬
Untie him.
‫فكّ وثاقه‬
– Yes, ma'am.
‫حاضر‬
Let me untie you.
‫سأفك الوثاق الآن‬
Where's Luffy?
‫أين لوفي؟‬
He cried all night. He's asleep now.
‫كان يبكي طوال اللّيل وهو نائم الآن‬
Boss! You have to see this!
‫أيّتها الزّعيمة! لن تصدّقي هذا!‬
I-It's a letter! From Sabo!
‫وردتنا رسالة من سابو‬
He must have sent a letter before setting out to sea!
‫لا بدّ أنّه أرسلها قبل ذهابه إلى البحر‬
Give me that.
‫أعطني إيّاها‬
I swear I won't go into the city. That letter is addressed to us, right?
‫لن أذهب إلى البلدة! إنّها لنا، أليس كذلك؟‬
Ace. Luffy. I hope you weren't hurt in the fire.
‫إيس، لوفي، آمل أنّكما لم تتأذّيا في الحريق"‬
I'm worried, but I'm sure you're okay.
‫أنا قلق بشأنكما لكن أعتقد أنّكما بخير‬
I'm sorry, guys, but by the time you get this letter, I'll already be...
‫آسف لقول هذا يا رفاق، لكن عندما‬ ‫تصلكما هذه الرّسالة، سأكون قد...‬
out at sea.
‫أبحرت بالفعل‬
A lot has happened, so I decided to set sail ahead of you guys.
‫حصل ما حصل وقرّرت أن أبحر قبلكما‬
My destination is anywhere but this country.
‫ستكون وجهتي أيّ مكان غير هذا المكان‬
There, I will become stronger.
‫سأصبح أقوى وسأصبح قرصانًا‬
Let's become the most free pirates ever,
‫علينا أن نصبح أكثر قراصنة أحرار على الإطلاق‬
and then the three of us should meet up again someday.
‫ونلتقي نحن الثّلاثة في مكان ما ثانيةً يومًا‬
Somewhere out on the vast open sea... We'll definitely meet again!
‫مكان في البحر الواسع! يومًا بالتأكيد!‬
Oh, and Ace...
‫بالمناسبة يا إيس، من منّا تظنّ أنّه الأخ الأكبر؟‬
Two big brothers and one little brother...
‫أخوان كبيران وأخ صغير‬
Maybe it's strange, but our bond is my treasure.
‫هذا غريب لكنّ أخوّتنا هي كنزي‬
Luffy might still be a weak crybaby, but...
‫ما زال لوفي طفلًا بكّاءً...‬
he's our little brother!
‫ولكن "إنّه أخونا الصّغير فاعتنِ به جيّدًا...‬